最初  宇宙是一片黑暗
In the beginning, there was darkness,
紧接着一声巨响  混沌初开
And then, bang...
时间  空间和物质
giving birth to an endless
开始不断膨胀
expanding existence of time, space and matter.
每天  我们都在解密这神秘莫测
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking the mysterious,
令人疯狂的极端之地
the mind-blowing, the deadly secrets of a place
宇宙
we call the universe.
日全食
A total eclipse.
一瞬间  光辉万丈的太阳
The brilliant sun suddenly obliterated
消失在月亮的暗面中
by the black disk of the Moon.
就像一颗眼珠正俯视着你
You can see this eyeball looking down at you.
日食既令人叹为观止  又让人惊心动魄
Both breathtaking and frightening,
它预示着2012年的太阳大风暴
eclipses warn us of powerful solar storms
可能使地球大混乱的古老预言成为现实
that may fulfill an ancient prophecy of chaos on Earth in 2012.
人类会陷入极度恐慌
People would freak out.
无法制冷
We wouldn't have refrigeration.
也不再有照明
We wouldn't have lights.
遥远恒星的日食现象揭示了新行星的存在
Eclipses of distant stars are now revealing new planets,
其中甚至有类地行星
even other Earths.
有些行星出其不意地出现在我们视野中
Some of them just popped right out at us.
探寻的范围包括整个宇宙空间
The search covers the entire universe,
却发端于地球表面
but it begins here on Earth,
此时太阳正隐没在日全食中
as the Sun hides its face in total eclipse.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制&调校:无影  字幕来源:人人影视  招募Q号:76846146
宇
宙
日 全 食
第5季　第7集
这个天空中的奇观
It's a spectacle in the sky
数千年来  人类为之着迷
that has enthralled human beings for thousands of years.
开始了  开始了
Here it comes. Here it comes.
开始了
Here it comes.
开始了  看那黑影
Here it comes. The shadow.
日全食
A total eclipse of the Sun.
有幸看见的人将对此永生难忘
Few people who see one will ever forget it.
亲眼目睹
Personally witnessing
日全食的亲身体验
a total solar eclipse in the flesh
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
加州大学伯克利分校
是一次神奇而令人敬畏的
is an amazing, awe-inspiring,
又极为感动的经历
tremendously moving experience.
从没有其他经历给我这样的感受
I've never experienced anything quite like it.
有些人  如天文学家格伦·施奈德
Some, Like astronomer Glenn Schneider,
是一小群不分时间地点在全球奔波
are part of a sub-culture of globe-hopping
追逐日食现象的人
eclipse chasers who will go anywhere, anytime to see an eclipse.
日食很吸引人  因为当天色变暗时
It grips you, because the sky has gone dark,
并不像午夜那么黑  而像是浓重的日暮
not as dark as midnight, but like a very deep twilight.
就像一颗眼珠正俯视着你
And you can see this eyeball looking down at you.
格伦·施奈德
亚利桑那大学
太阳表面的黑影正是月球的轮廓
The black disk where the Sun was is the silhouette of the Moon.
令人难以置信的是
It's an experience that you can't believe
整个过程仅持续一两分钟
it was only a minute or two minutes.
恍如漫长一生  实则短短一瞬
It seems to have lasted a lifetime and also just an instant.
这个令人振奋的现象是太空探索的起点
This compelling event is a launching pad for cosmic exploration,
藉此将解开一系列长久困惑着人类的奥秘
solving a string of mysteries that have puzzled mankind for ages.
是什么让太阳在毫无征兆的情况下消失呢
What makes the Sun disappear without warning?
这种现象何时发生
When does it happen?
我们如何预测它
How can we predict it?
人类能否自己制造日食
Can we make it happen ourselves?
这些问题一旦得到解答  我们会发现
Once understood, we find that each eclipse
每次日食都提供了关于宇宙的全新信息
reveals something new about the universe.
如今我们在寻找远恒星的最新日食现象
Even now, we're finding our newest eclipses around distant stars,
并发现太阳系外行星
revealing extra-solar planets,
其中可能有类地行星
some, perhaps twins to the Earth,
拥有孕育生命的可能
with the potential for life.
故事记载始于地球上的日食之谜
The story begins with the mystery of our own eclipses,
即光天化日之下  太阳突然间消失
a sun suddenly vanishing in broad daylight.
早在有历史记载之前
Visible since before recorded history,
我们的祖先对日食充满了好奇与恐惧
the ancients regarded eclipses with wonder and fear.
古人没有客观地意识到
The ancient people didn't understand physically
日食是怎样一种现象
what was going on during a solar eclipse.
他们看见的是太阳上逐渐变大的缺口
They would see a progressively bigger bite being taken out of the Sun,
似乎天神或毒龙吞咬着太阳
as though some gods or dragons were eating the Sun,
向人类表达他们的愤怒
mad at those people.
因此人们击打锅碗瓢盆
So the people would beat pots and pans
大声喊叫甚至以处女祭祀
and yell and scream and sacrifice virgins
以诸如此类的行为来平息神怒
and all sorts of things to appease the gods
或吓跑毒龙
and scare the dragons away.
结果呢
And you know what?
每次都奏效了
It worked every time.
数千年来
Through thousands of years,
通过对天空中日月轨迹的耐心观测
patiently watching the movements of the Sun and the Moon in the sky,
古代的天文学家们终于明白
ancient astronomers realized eclipses happen
当月球运转到太阳正前方时日食便发生了
when the Moon passed directly in front of the Sun.
最后学者们通过对日食规律的长期研究
In time, scholars studied the patterns of eclipses
已能预测其发生的时间
long enough to predict them.
早在22个世纪前 古巴比伦人
The Babylonians discovered what's called the Saros cycle
就发现了沙罗周期
more than 22 centuries ago.
沙罗周期就是日食周期
The Saros cycle is a cycle of eclipses
这个周期每223个月循环一次
that repeat every 223 months,
也就是18年一轮
roughly every 18 years,
每个周期之间都非常相似
and they're very similar to one another.
古希腊人了解到了古巴比伦人的这一发现
The Greeks were aware of the Babylonian discovery,
这一点从安提凯希拉装置上就能看出
as we've learned from the remarkable antikythera mechanism,
它出自1901年地中海海底的沉船
an ancient device found on a shipwreck under the Mediterranean sea in 1901.
安提凯希拉装置一开始被认为是
The antikythera mechanism was first thought to be
某种时间计或天体计时器
some sort of a clock and then some sort of celestial timer.
这个极为复杂的装置
It was a very complex mechanism
由许多齿轮  叠层和平面构成
with many gears and layers and planes.
自其发现以来  考古学家们对
Archaeologists have been intrigued
安提凯希拉装置充满兴趣
by the antikythera mechanism ever since it was found.
几十年前  他们终于发现
Decades ago, they understood
这个机械模拟计算器
it was a mechanical computer
用于测算行星的运动轨迹
for calculating movements of the planets,
月相以及其他天象
phases of the Moon and other astronomical phenomena.
但最近的发现令他们瞠目结舌
But the latest discovery astounded them.
2008年  他们通过三维X光术及电脑断层扫描
In 2008, using 3-D X-rays and CT scans,
发现这个装置里
they found that the Babylonian Saros cycle
包含了古巴比伦的沙罗周期
was built into the device.
该装置的两块底板上刻有
In two of the back plates of the mechanism was inscribed
一个有着分区的螺旋形标志
a spiral-like figure that had divisions,
把它们放在一起
that when you added them up,
对应的就是沙罗周期的月份
corresponded to the months in a Saros cycle.
把沙罗周期包含到该装置里的唯一原因
The only reason to have the Saros built into the mechanism
就是该装置也应用于预测日食
was if it was an eclipse predictor as well.
平均每16个月就可以在地球上
A total eclipse of the Sun can be seen somewhere on Earth
某个位置看到一次全日食
an average of once every 16 months.
如今  预测日食已是精确的科学
Today, predicting them is a very exact science.
美国本土下一次可见的日全食
The next total solar eclipse to be visible
将发生在2017年8月21日
from the United States will be on August 21, 2017.
但是如今的天文学家能够提供的
But modern astronomers can do much better
已不仅仅是日食的日期
than supplying the date for an eclipse.
一张日食地图显示出了人们在2017年
An eclipse map shows the exact path
能够看到的日全食的精确轨迹
along which people can see the 2017 total eclipse.
时间精确到秒
And the timing is down to the second.
日全食阴影将于上午
It will reach totality
10点17分18秒抵达俄勒冈州塞勒姆市
at 10:17 plus 18 seconds A.M. In Salem, Oregon;
下午1点15分55秒抵达密苏里州圣路易
and 1:15:55 P.M. in St. Louis, Missouri;
然后于2点41分55秒到达南卡罗莱纳的哥伦比亚
and 2:41:55 in Columbia, South Carolina.
这条轨迹将用时一小时31分1.6秒横跨美国
It will cross the country in 1 hour, 31 minutes and 1.6 seconds
平均宽度66公里
along a path averaging 66 miles wide.
有这么精准的时间测定
With information so exact,
任何想看日食的人都可以如愿以偿
anyone who wants to see it will be able to.
届时全美国的人们都有机会
People will have an opportunity to get to the path of totality
来到这条日全食的路线
from all over the United States.
每个人都值得一试
That's an opportunity that everybody should really try to take
因为这样的机会稀少而且是百年难求
because they're few and far between.
来了  开始了  瞧
Here it comes. Here it comes. Here it comes.
除了壮观华丽的视觉景象
Apart from the spectacular visible picture,
被遮挡的太阳还将带给观赏者
the blocked sun also gives viewers
真实冰彻的感官体验
the chills in a literal sense.
在日全食期间
During a total solar eclipse,
温度会直降35度
the temperature can drop as much as 35 degrees.
这与外太空的低温  自然没有可比性
That, of course, is nothing compared to the temperatures in outer space,
在那里  这种遮挡无处不在
where all the action is taking place.
宇宙到底有多冷
How cold can the universe get?
这也是来自科罗拉多州博尔德市的的卡罗
That's what Carlo of Boulder, Colorado,
想要"问问宇宙"的问题
wanted to "ask the universe",
所以他给我们发了电子邮件
so he e-mailed us.
宇宙目前的温度是多少
What is the current temperature of the universe,
为什么那么冷
and why is it so cold?
卡罗  这问题可真冷啊
Carlo, that's a really cool question,
容我调侃一下
if you'll pardon my pun.
因为离太阳很近  我们的感觉是温暖的
Here near the Sun, we feel warm,
但是在外太空
but in outer space,
宇宙的温度
the temperature of the universe
只有绝对三度[绝对零度的相对三度]
is only three degrees above absolute zero.
真的是非常的冷
It's really cold.
之所以这么冷  可以这样来理解
It's that cold because the universe
将宇宙理解为一团扩展开来的气体
can be thought of as an expanding gas,
而这团气体已经扩展冷却了140亿年
and it's been expanding and cooling for 14 billion years.
日全食之所以难得一见
The reason total eclipses are few and far between
是由于天体之间的相互作用非常微妙
is the result of a delicate astronomical interplay.
之所以形成日全食  是因为
It depends on a moon
月亮与地球的距离大约为24万英里
that's an average of about 240,000 miles away
而且月亮的直径约为地球的1/4
and one-quarter the diameter of the Earth.
我来演示一下产生日食的难度
To demonstrate just how difficult it is
要把两个天体排在一条线上才行
to get two objects to align just right to create an eclipse,
霍莉·吉尔伯特
美国宇航局戈达德太空飞行中心
这个乒乓球代表地球
I'm gonna use this ping-pong ball representing the Earth
这个非常小的弹珠代表月亮
and this very small marble representing the Moon.
这弹珠这么小以至于我不得不用镊子夹住
This is so small that I have to hold it in tweezers
才能让你们看清楚
for you to be able to see.
那么  假设地球和月球
Now, the Earth and the Moon
在太空中的距离大概是这么远
are located about this far apart in space,
这就使得它们很难
and it makes it very difficult for them
恰好与太阳排成一条直线
to align just right with the Sun
以造成日食现象
to create an eclipse as I'm going to demonstrate.
若要刚好排在恰当的直线上以产生日食
It's very difficult to get these to align just right
非常困难
for an eclipse to occur.
然而一旦成功了
But once I do,
就能看到乒乓球上有个模糊的阴影
I can see a fuzzy shadow on this ping-pong ball
这和从太空中拍摄的美丽的日食图
that looks very much like the beautiful photographs
非常相似
of solar eclipses from space.
这一块巨大而模糊的阴影被称为半影
The large, fuzzy part of the shadow is called the penumbra.
日食期间  如果你所处的是半影部分
If you're standing in the penumbra during an eclipse,
那么看到的太阳并不是被完全遮挡的
the Sun is not completely covered,
而是日偏食
and you see a partial eclipse.
中间的一小块黑影被称作本影
The small, dark, central part of the shadow is called the umbra.
如果你所处的是本影部分
If you're standing in it,
那么太阳就被完全遮挡
the Sun is completely covered,
你看到的就是日全食
and you see the total eclipse.
由于月球的公转运动
Because of the Moon's motion in its orbit,
本影在地球上移动
the umbra moves across the Earth,
形成清晰的轨迹线  即全食带
tracing a clear line called the path of totality,
只有在这个区域内才能看到真正的日全食
the only place where a true total eclipse is visible.
本影的宽度往往不到100公里
The width of the umbra is typically under 100 miles.
因此你必须精确地选择观影位置
So you really have to position yourself carefully
这样才能看到日全食
in order to see a totally eclipsed Sun.
看到97%或者98%的日偏食
And seeing a 97 or a 98% eclipse
与看到100%日全食的效果不可同日而语
is nowhere near seeing a 100% eclipsed sun.
你必须准确地呆在全食带以内才行
You've got to be in the path of totality.
除了日月形成的日食现象
There is much more to the eclipse phenomenon
宇宙中还有很多的此类现象
than just the Sun and the Moon.
星体的这种互动遍布全宇宙
The story reaches across the universe,
因为蚀的确无处不在
because eclipses do happen everywhere.
当有星体运行到地球和另外一颗星体之间
An eclipse occurs whenever one object passes between us
切断了后者的光源  就形成了星蚀
and another object, cutting off its light.
实际上  所有其他有卫星的行星
Virtually all other planets with moons
也会有蚀现象
will also have solar eclipses,
不管它们是从属于太阳系
whether they occur here in our own solar system
还是运行在茫茫宇宙的其他恒星系中
or around other stars across the entire expanse of space.
但是这一瑰丽的宇宙现象
But what can this eye candy of the cosmos
能教给我们什么呢
teach us about the universe?
仅凭一个简单的日食  如何能够证明
How is it possible that a simple eclipse on the Earth
阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦关于时空扭曲的怪异理论
can prove that the bizarre distortions of space and time
本质上是正确的呢
predicted by Albert Einstein are essentially correct?
我们对日全食的探索
Our search for total eclipses
基于地面上的观测
begins with what we witness from the Earth.
而在太空中  人造卫星却利用日食
In space, satellites use eclipses of our Sun
来监测类似于2012年太阳风暴这样的灾难
to watch for disasters like the fabled solar storms of 2012.
然而  在遥不可及的太空
But farther out in the cosmos,
人类的探索已经揭示  蚀现象无处不在
our explorations reveal that there are eclipses everywhere,
其中许多是解开更多的宇宙秘密的钥匙
many of them keys to unlocking secrets of the universe.
在太阳系
In the solar system,
唯一没有蚀现象的行星
the only planets without eclipses
是水星和金星  因为它们没有卫星
are Mercury and Venus because they have no moons.
目前  太阳系中已知的运行卫星
Currently, there's about 170 known moons
有170颗左右
orbiting planets in our solar system.
但如今  其数目持续增长
Now, that number keeps on growing.
已知土星和木星各有至少60颗卫星
Saturn and Jupiter each have at least 60 known moons.
但是随着我们的数据愈发精确
But as we get better and better data,
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
加州大学伯克利分校
更多的小型卫星逐渐被发现
additional small moons are being found.
因此我认为太阳系中有着成百上千的卫星
So I think there are hundreds of moons in the solar system.
大多数情况下
In most cases,
这些卫星太小而无法完全遮挡太阳
the moons are too small to block the full disk of the Sun.
火星就是一个很好的例子
Mars is a good example.
根据火星漫游者机器人拍摄的表面照片
Taken from the surface by the Opportunity Rover,
这些来自美国宇航局的照片展现了
these NASA photos show the
火星的卫星火卫一从太阳前面穿过时的情景
Martian moon Phobos as it moves across the Sun.
这表明  我们在地球上看到的日食
It turns out that the eclipses we see here on Earth
是与众不同的
are like no others.
要理解地球上发生的蚀
In order to get the kind of eclipse that we have here on Earth,
亚当·弗兰克
罗切斯特大学
尤其是日全食
where it's a total eclipse,
月球和太阳的位置会刚好吻合
but the Moon just fits over the Sun
因此你还能够看到日冕
so that you can see the corona,
这太神奇了
How dramatic that is,
必须是一条大小距离都非常精准的直线
requires a remarkable alignment of size and distance.
这是发生在宇宙中的一种巧合
It amounts to a coincidence of cosmic proportions.
太阳是月球大小的四百倍
The Sun is about 400 times bigger than the Moon.
然而  太阳离地球的距离恰好是
But the Sun also happens to be
月球距地球距离的四百倍
about 400 times farther away from the Earth than the Moon.
那就意味着太阳和月球
What that means is that both the Sun and the Moon appear
在天空中仿佛是大小相等的
to be almost exactly the same size in the sky.
它们在空中的大小决定了日食的产生
Their sizes in the sky are crucial for eclipses.
假设这个球代表太阳
Suppose this ball represents the Sun
这个小红球代表月球
and the small red ball represents the Moon.
要想形成日全食
To get a total solar eclipse,
它们彼此之间以及地球
they have to be perfectly lined up
必须完美地排成一条直线
with each other and with the Earth.
现在  如果这样
Now, in this case,
由于月球距离地球非常的远
the Moon is too far from the Earth,
而显得体积太小  无法完全覆盖住太阳表面
so it looks too small to fully cover the Sun's disk.
但是当我使月球逐渐靠近地球之后
but as I bring the Moon closer to the Earth,
月球看起来就越来越大了
the Moon looks bigger and bigger.
最终
Now, eventually,
当月球距离地球足够近的时候
the Moon is close enough to the Earth
它也就能够将太阳表面完美的覆盖住
that it perfectly covers the Sun's disk.
这就是一次完整的日全食
That's a perfect total solar eclipse.
这万众瞩目的日月地一条线的发生
What are the chances that this remarkable alignment
刚好被另一个行星上的智慧生物
would happen on a planet at just the time in its history
看到并感到好奇而想一探究竟的
when an intelligent species has evolved to witness
发生几率是多少呢
and wonder about the results?
探究是否在银河系中
It's interesting to speculate
是否还另有其他智慧生物
whether any other intelligent beings
也同样经历着这美妙精彩的日全食
in our milky way galaxy experience
这是一件非常有趣的事情
such beautiful, perfect, total solar eclipses.
我们或许是宇宙中唯一的
It's really quite possible that we may be the only
能够欣赏到此类天体排成一条直线的景观的智慧生物
intelligent species in the entire universe that has this kind of alignment,
因为这真的太独特了
because it is so specific.
古代的人们曾经一度很畏惧
And while ancient humans once dreaded
会把太阳隐藏起来的日食
solar eclipses for hiding the Sun.
另一类的蚀现象回答了
Another kind of eclipse helped to answer
一个最基本的问题
what was once a fundamental question:
地球到底是平的还是圆的
Is the Earth flat, or is it round?
当地球和月亮在天空中的角色互换之后
The puzzle was solved when the Earth and Moon
这个谜随即迎刃而解
went into a celestial role reversal.
那就是月食
The result was a lunar eclipse.
当眼看着地球的影子经过月球时
By watching the shadow of the Earth pass across the Moon,
古人们可以真实的看到
the ancients were able to actually see that
影子是呈曲线状
the shadow was curved.
因此他们能够推断
Therefore, they were able to infer that
既然影子是曲线的
since the shadow was curved,
那么地球也应当是球形的
the Earth itself must also be spherical.
当地球的部分影子穿过月球时
The curvature is prominent when only part of
影子的弯曲程度格外地明显
the Earth's shadow passes across the Moon.
当月球完全被地球的影子遮住时
But when the Moon is entirely shadowed by the Earth,
也就发生了月全食
the lunar eclipse is total.
月全食就发生在
A total lunar eclipse occurs
月球移动到地球的影子当中之后
when the Moon passes within the shadow cast by the Earth.
月球整个被地球的影子所遮挡
So the Moon is completely in the shadow of the Earth.
每个人从地球的背光面
Everyone from the dark side of the Earth
都可以看到月全食
can see the totally eclipsed Moon.
也就是说  很大一部分人都能看到月食
That means a vast population can see a lunar eclipse,
但是只有很少一部分人可以看到日全食
whereas only a small number of people can see a total solar eclipse.
月食能够帮助科学家们
Lunar eclipses also helped scientists
探究光的散射
learn about the scattering of light.
在月全食时
In a total lunar eclipse,
月球变成了橘红色
the Moon turns red-orange.
月球确实是在地球的影子当中
It is in the Earth's shadow.
但是一些由太阳散发出来的光线穿过了大气层
But some light from the Sun scatters through the atmosphere.
光线在大气层中穿透了很大一段距离
The light, passing through a great distance of atmosphere,
因此就像太阳位于地平线时一样也变红了
turns red just as it does on Earth when the Sun is on the horizon.
光线透过厚实的大气层
The light travels through its greatest thickness of atmosphere
形成了日出日落时的红霞
and creates a red sunrise or sunset.
事实上  每一种蚀现象
In fact, every kind of eclipse
都让我们学习到了关于宇宙的科学
has much to teach us about the science of the universe.
在二十世纪早期
In the early 20th century,
美国总统柯立芝在白宫见证的一次日食
one solar eclipse, witnessed at the White House by President Coolidge,
首次证实了一个预言
gave us the first confirmation of a prediction
预言来自一位年轻科学家阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦
made by a young scientist named Albert Einstein.
1919年  宇航员阿瑟·艾丁顿
In 1919, the astronomer Arthur Eddington
去到了日全食的观测地
went to the location of a total solar eclipse
以验证爱因斯坦广义相对论的预言
to test a prediction of Einstein's general theory of relativity.
1915年  爱因斯坦发表了他的预言
In 1915, Einstein published his prediction
引力可以导致空间发生弯曲
that gravity causes space to curve,
并且那些由星星发出的光线
and the light from stars would
也会随着空间的弯曲而弯曲
bend following that curve.
所以  当空中的一颗星星靠近太阳时
So if there were a star close to the Sun in the sky,
它的光线会由于受到太阳的引力而弯曲
its light would be bent by the Sun's gravity.
唯一能够检验爱因斯坦预言的方法
The only way to test Einstein's prediction
就是等到日食  当太阳变暗
was during an eclipse, when the Sun was darkened
并且周围的星星都看不到的时候
and the nearby stars were visible.
艾丁顿深知  一颗应当会被太阳挡住
Eddington knew the accurate position of a star
的星星所在的具体位置
that should have been blocked by the Sun.
但是如果太阳的引力弯曲了星星的光线
But if the Sun's gravity bent the star's light,
就如爱因斯坦所说
as Einstein said,
看起来这颗星星将会出现在另一个位置
it would be seen as if it were in a different position altogether.
艾丁顿测量出并且目睹了这一现象
Eddington measured that, he saw that,
从而首次证实了
thus confirming, for the first time,
爱因斯坦的广义相对论所作出的预言
a prediction of Einstein's general theory of relativity.
但是日全食对于科学探索的最大贡献是
But the greatest scientific benefit of total solar eclipses
日全食让我们看到了日冕
is the view they give us of the Sun's corona,
它原本是无法看到的
which is otherwise invisible to us.
如果没有日全食的发生
Without the occurrence of total solar eclipses,
我们甚至可能
it's really questionable today
连太阳外围有一层日冕都不知道
whether we would actually even know that the Sun had a corona,
格伦·施奈德
亚利桑那大学
那是一层在外围的炙热稀薄的气体
an outer, hot, tenuous atmosphere.
太阳表面的亮度
The solar disk is a million times brighter
是周围日冕的一百万倍
than the surrounding corona.
如果不将太阳表面遮挡住
And so if you don't block that out,
你根本看不到日冕
you can't visibly see the corona.
对于我们而言  观测到日冕之所以重要
For us to be able to observe the corona is important
是因为否则我们就不知道
because otherwise we wouldn't know
太阳大气的这一层向外绵延至太空中
that this layer of the solar atmosphere extends out into space.
霍莉·吉尔伯特
美国宇航局戈达德太空飞行中心
事实上  我们在地球上
And, in fact, we're embedded, here on Earth,
是被太阳向外延伸的大气层日冕所包围的
in the solar atmosphere in the extended solar corona.
在望远镜发明后的三百多年里
For more than three centuries after the invention of the telescope,
天文学家跑遍全世界
astronomers rushed to far flung locations all over the world
只是为了花几分钟观察研究
just to spend a few minutes observing, studying
和分析神秘的日冕
and analyzing the mysterious corona.
这种状态持续到科学技术的飞跃
And it stayed that way until the technological leap
可以实现人造日食
that gave mankind the power to make its own eclipses.
这些人造日食揭示了一些完全出乎意料的事情
These artificial eclipses revealed something totally unexpected:
被证明是太阳系最剧烈的爆炸的
Eruptions in space that turned out
日冕喷发活动
to be the greatest explosions in the solar system.
形形色色的日食被证明是
Eclipses of every kind have proven to be keys
解开宇宙中各种秘密的钥匙
to unlocking many of the secrets scattered across the universe.
日食让我们发现遥远星系的行星
Eclipses reveal planets circling distant stars,
以及太阳风暴对地球的破坏力超乎我们想象
and solar storms posing dangers to Earth, worse than we can imagine.
太阳的威胁隐藏在日冕中
The Sun's threats are hidden in the corona,
地球上只有在日全食时才能观察到它
which appears on Earth only during a total eclipse.
它平均十六个月才发生一次
It happens only once every 16 months on average,
而且地球上只有有限的地方能观察到
at places scattered across the entire globe,
远不足以让我们发现这种致命的危险
not nearly enough for monitoring such a deadly hazard.
然而在太空中  卫星为我们传送
Out in space, though, satellites send us
最细微的太阳活动图片
up to the minute pictures of the Sun.
壮观的太空探测器给我们展示了光芒四射的日冕
Spectacular space probes show the solar corona in all its glory,
再也不用去等待日食
and never ever have to wait for an eclipse.
秘密就在于
Their secret is a piece of technology
人造日食的科技
that creates a manmade eclipse.
比如说我们想看看太阳
Let's say I wanna look at the Sun,
格伦·施奈德
亚利桑那大学
它就在我旁边这里
which is right next to me here.
太阳真的很明亮  它在空中放射无数的光芒
The Sun is really bright and it scatters lots of light in the sky,
如此多以至于我无法看清它的轮廓
so much so that I can't see what's around it.
但如果我用一个仪器  例如眼镜店用的遮光器
But if I use a device like an occluder that an optician might use,
我能用它来遮挡阳光
I can use it to block the Sunlight,
消除炫目的光从而观察太阳周围是什么
kill the glare and see what's around the Sun.
此方法也可以用于观察恒星
I can do the same thing with stars.
这种仪器我们统称为日冕仪
And a device like that that we can put together is called a coronagraph.
用于研究太阳的日冕
We use it for studying the Sun's corona,
以及恒星的环境
and we use it for studying the environments of stars.
发明于1939年的日冕仪
Coronagraphs, invented in 1939,
起初用于地球上的望远镜上
were first applied to telescopes on Earth.
它们在海拔最高处时效果最好
They worked best at the highest altitudes
那里大气对阳光的削弱作用最小
where scattering of sunlight by the atmosphere is minimized.
但日冕仪在太空中发挥的作用最大
But coronagraphs do their heaviest lifting in space.
配备日冕仪的航天器主要是
Two of the major missions carrying coronagraphs are
太阳风层探测器和日地关系天文台
the SOHO and STEREO spacecraft.
SOHO:Solar and Heliospheric Observatory
STEREO:Solar Terrestrial Relations Observatory
它们拍摄延伸到很远处的日冕活动
They photograph the corona out to great distances
并且能拍下一些现象
and pick up other phenomena
如果没有人造日食就不可能发觉这些现象
that, without these artificial eclipses, would be totally unseen.
卫星获得的太阳影像
Movies of the Sun obtained by satellites
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
加州大学伯克利分校
真的很吸引人
are really fascinating to watch
因为你能看到日冕结构中的
because you can see all sorts of changes
各种变化
in the structure of the corona,
日珥和耀斑等等
and prominences and flares and things like that.
你还能看到被称作掠过太阳的彗星
And you can also see what's called sun-grazing comets...
彗星飞过来差点撞到太阳  然而呼啸而过
Comets that come in and nearly hit the Sun, but go whizzing past.
它们太靠近太阳
They're too close to the Sun
所以在黑夜或者白天都无法看到
to be visible during the nighttime or the daytime,
但在遮住太阳后
but with the Sun's disc blocked out,
你就能看到它们了
you can actually see them.
1971年  美国宇航局的一颗装备了日冕仪的卫星
In 1971, a NASA satellite, equipped with a coronagraph,
拍下了这些完全未知的图像
snapped these shots of something completely unknown.
这些粒状的图像揭示了闻所未闻的
The grainy pictures revealed an explosion in the corona
日冕中的一次爆炸
no one had ever seen before.
1971年  一台在卫星上的日冕仪发现
In 1971, it was discovered with a coronagraph on a satellite
太阳有时候会出现
that the Sun sometimes undergoes
一种叫做日冕物质抛射的现象
what's called Coronal Mass Ejections,
爆炸威力无比强大
incredibly powerful explosions,
如同引爆了数十亿颗核弹
like billions of nuclear bombs going off,
从太阳中喷发出高速的带电粒子
that eject high-speed charged particles from the Sun.
太阳粒子以高速向地球飞来
The solar particles speed toward the Earth,
形成了美丽的极光
where they cause the beautiful auroras,
它们通常出现在两极附近
usually seen near the poles.
但它们也能严重破坏卫星
But they can also seriously damage satellites,
通信系统以及电力系统
communications and power grids.
日冕物质抛射也称CMES  发生在日冕层
Coronal Mass Ejections or CMES happen in the corona,
经常和发生在太阳表面的
and are often linked to solar flares,
太阳耀斑联系在一起
which happen on the Sun's surface.
这些是目前太阳系中已知的
These are currently the most powerful explosions
最强大的爆炸
known in the solar system,
接近十亿颗氢弹爆炸的威力
approaching the power of a billion hydrogen bombs.
日冕物质抛射涉及如此多的物质
Coronal mass ejections involve so much mass
霍莉·吉尔伯特
美国宇航局戈达德太空飞行中心
从太阳发出如此强大的电磁能
and magnetic energy moving away from the Sun.
以至于它们的宽度几乎达到太阳的一半
They can be as wide as almost half of the Sun.
它就像是个巨大的含有各种物质
And it's like a large bubble of material
和电磁能的气泡  从太阳中发出
and magnetic field moving away from the Sun
时速达到四百万多英里
at over four million miles an hour.
太阳抛射出的物质量是巨大的
The amount of solar material ejected is huge.
一次日冕物质抛射
During a CME,
相当于20万艘二战时期战舰的物质
mass equivalent to 200,000 world war II battleships
被抛到太空中
is thrown out into space...
即2200亿磅的物质
220 billion pounds of matter.
2003年10月
October 2003,
日冕层发生了一系列强大的日冕物质抛射
a powerful series of CMES erupts in the solar corona.
它是近期最强烈的喷发之一
One of the most intense in recent memory.
产生的极光远至南部的佛罗里达
It generates auroras seen as far South as Florida.
引起了至少一次全球电力故障
It causes at least one power blackout on Earth
并影响了美国宇航局超过一半的卫星
and affects more than half of NASA's space missions.
太阳风层探测器暂时失灵
The Soho solar satellite is briefly disabled
但生动地记录下了此次事件的画面
but records dramatic pictures of the event.
在卫星图像中
In the satellite images,
你能看到高能粒子击中探测器
you can see the energetic particles hitting the detector,
看起来像是一连串的雪花片
and it looks like there's a bunch of snow.
所以我们能看到粒子影响了卫星本身
So we can actually see the particles impacting the satellite itself.
但也许这些太阳风暴的危险超过我们的想象
But there may be more danger in these solar storms than we suspect.
我们不知道这些大抛射多久发生一次
We don't yet know how often the big ones happen.
但最近的研究告诉我们最糟糕的情形是
But the latest research tells us the worst case scenario
一阵太阳风暴猛烈冲击地球
could smash the Earth with a solar wind,
能造成数百万人死亡
whose effects could kill millions.
在宇宙中
Across the depths of the cosmos,
每当卫星或行星运转经过恒星
whenever moons or planets cross paths with stars,
就会发生壮观的蚀现象
the result is an often revealing
发人深省  有时甚至令人敬畏
and sometimes awe-inspiring spectacle of an eclipse.
在地球上  人造日食
Here on Earth, manmade artificial eclipses
已经发现了太阳风暴无与伦比的破坏力
have uncovered solar storms of incomparable violence.
观测日冕物质抛射至关重要
It is critical that we watch for coronal mass ejections,
使用日冕仪遮住太阳表面
massive solar outbursts discovered using coronagraphs
从而可以发现日冕物质抛射
blocking out the disk of the Sun.
当太阳黑子周期达到高峰
The greatest danger comes
最大的危机来临了
when the solar sunspot cycle is at its maximum,
大概每11年为一个周期
roughly every 11 years.
在太阳活动的高峰期间
During the maximum of solar activities,
也许每天都会有两三次大的日冕物质抛射
there might be two or three coronal mass ejections per day,
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
加州大学伯克利分校
然而在低潮期
whereas during a minimum in the cycle,
也许每周只有一次
there might be only one per week.
太阳低潮期
太阳高峰期
科学家们在留心观察下一次太阳高峰
Scientists are on the lookout for the next solar maximum,
有些人认为那会是在2012年
which some believe would come in 2012.
正好是玛雅历结束的时候
that happens to be the year the Mayan calendar comes to an end,
这件事引起了普遍的推测
which has given rise to widespread speculation
认为那年会有一场全球性的大灾难
about a global disaster in that year.
实际上  现在认为即将到来的太阳高峰
In fact, it's now believed the coming solar maximum
将是自1928年以来最弱的一次
will be the weakest since 1928
2012年后才会到来
and won't be reached until after 2012.
尽管现在的科学还无法精确预期
Although precise dating is beyond the realm of today's science.
现在预测下个太阳高峰
It is now predicted that the next solar maximum
将大约会在2014年初达到顶峰
will peak in probably early 2014.
霍莉·吉尔伯特
美国宇航局戈达德太空飞行中心
一些人认为还要早些
Some people predict it will happen before that.
但是它是一种不断变化的目标
But it's a sort of a moving target
因为我们并不完全理解太阳周期
because we don't fully understand the solar cycle itself.
科学家们很早就怀疑会有一次超级日冕物质抛射
Scientists have long suspected that a super CME,
当它发生的时候就会是一场大灾难
when it does happen, could be disastrous.
最近的一次朝向地球的大抛射是在1859年
The last such event to target the Earth happened in 1859,
令电报通讯中断
disrupting telegraph service
形成的极光在赤道也能看见
and creating auroras visible down to the equator.
今天  这样的事件意味着
An event like that today would mean
我们从未经历过的大范围的供电中断
power outages on a scale we've never experienced.
美国电力网的大部分将中断三个月
Much of the U.S. Power Grid could be down for three months
也许更久
and perhaps much longer.
如果我们断电三个月甚至更久
If we lost electricity for three months or more,
其后果  尤其是对于我们这样的
the effects, especially on a country like ours
如此依赖电力的国家  将会是灭顶之灾
that depends on electricity so much, would be devastating.
你只能想象可能会是什么样
You can only imagine what it would be like.
人们会崩溃的  真的
People would freak out, really.
我是说  我们将没有制冷
I mean, we wouldn't have refrigeration.
没有照明
We wouldn't have lights.
如果没有太阳能卫星造成的人造日食
Without the artificial eclipses in our solar satellites,
我们可能连有这样的危险存在都不知道
we would have no idea that such a threat even existed.
根据最近的估计
According to recent estimates,
无油供应
完全恢复需要四到十年
full recovery could take 4 to 10 years.
数百万人将会死于
Millions of people could die due to
食物  净水和药物短缺
shortages of food, clean water and pharmaceuticals.
相关损失大概会达到1到2万亿美元
Projected damage may be as much as $1 to $2 trillion,
相当于20场卡特里娜飓风
comparable to 20 Hurricane Katrinas.
一次超级日冕物质抛射在150年前攻击地球
A super CME struck the Earth 150 years ago,
但是科学家们对下一次爆发的时间意见不一
but scientists disagree on when the next one could come.
在我们有生之年发生的可能性
The likelihood of that happening in our lifetime
并不让人愉快  但是我们只是不知道
is probably not that good, but we just don't know.
我们没有足够的资料
We don't have enough data.
威力最强大的日冕物质抛射
The most powerful coronal mass ejections
能造成全球范围的灾难
that could cause widespread damage over all of Earth
也许大约一千年才发生一次
probably occur only about once every millennium or so.
然而  千年难遇的巨大灾难
Nevertheless, having a huge calamity
真是个大事件
every few thousand years is really a big deal.
我们最好的保护措施也许是人造日食
Our best protection may be in the artificial eclipses
在宇宙飞船上监控日冕物质抛射
aboard spacecraft monitoring the Sun for CMES.
如果改进后的警报系统投入使用
If improved warning systems are put into place,
我们也许有足够的时间切断电网
we may have enough time to shut down the electric grid
以免它起火
to prevent it from burning out,
避开致命的子弹  否则就直接向我们来了
dodging the deadly bullet otherwise aimed straight for us.
日冕物质抛射也许是
A coronal mass ejection may be
日食科学发现的最壮观的现象
the most spectacular phenomenon uncovered by eclipse science.
但是宇宙充满了各种其他蚀
But the universe is full of other eclipses,
每一种都教给我们一些关于宇宙的东西
each one teaching us something else about the cosmos.
甚至一次不比月球更远的短途空间旅行
Even a short hop into space, no farther than the Moon,
就能改变局面
turns the tables on us,
让地球成为造成日食的天体
as the Earth becomes the celestial body to eclipse the Sun.
想想阿波罗12号图像是多么重要
Think about how important that Apollo 12 image was,
亚当·弗兰克
罗切斯特大学
如果他们把相机对着地球
Were they turned the camera back towards the Earth
你会看到地球造成的日食
and you could see the Earth eclipsing the Sun.
阿波罗号发回的图像对人类来说是里程碑式的
Those images from Apollo were really epic-making for humanity.
它让我们第一次真正意识到
It gave us our first real sense
地球就是一个漂浮在太空的物体
of the Earth as being an object floating in space.
更远点
Farther out,
卡西尼空间探测器在土星上看太阳
the Cassini space probe looks at Saturn,
几乎是黑色
virtually black
被背光式的环围绕着  或者说封闭着
surrounded by backlit rings as it blocks out the disk of the Sun
距离太阳将近十亿英里远
nearly a billion miles away.
与我们的月亮造成的日食完全不同的景象
A very different view of our own moon eclipsing the Sun
来自于Stereo-b宇宙飞船
comes from the Stereo-b spacecraft.
从空间深处看来  月亮似乎小很多
From deep space, the Moon appears much smaller,
它越过太阳的表面  称为凌日
And it crosses the Sun's disk in what's called a transit.
这种日食也许是回答我们问题的关键
This kind of eclipse may be pivotal in answering our questions
关于宇宙中还有什么
about who else may be out there in the universe.
凌日之所以如此重要
What makes transit so important
是因为  它是我们
is it's one of our ways
真正发现太阳系外的
of actually discovering what are called extra-solar planets,
围绕其他恒星旋转的行星的方式之一
planets orbiting other stars.
这种诱人的可能性由于
The tantalizing possibility is tempered
实行起来过于困难而令人气馁
by the daunting problem of actually making it work.
发现一颗从恒星前面穿过的行星
Finding a planet transiting in front of its star
就像看见一只跳蚤穿过车前灯一样稀罕
is like seeing a flea crawling across an auto's headlight.
但是科学发展日新月异
But science is rising to the challenge
新的太空望远镜在观察微小的蚀现象方面有所改善
and new space telescopes trained on the tiny eclipses
为发现围绕远距离恒星的行星提供了条件
that uncover planets around distant stars are about to strike gold.
几个世纪的疑惑之后
After centuries of wondering,
在宇宙深处发现第二个地球
the discovery of another Earth in the depths of space
突然变得触手可及
is suddenly within reach.
如果对于蚀的研究
If the search for eclipses
是从地球上最壮观的日食开始的
starts with the most spectacular examples here on Earth,
将我们的观察转向太空  发现了其他的蚀
turning our view out into space reveals other eclipses,
不仅在太阳系内  而且更远得多
not only in the solar system but far beyond,
它们有助于解决天文学的研究热点之一
where they're key to one of astronomy's hottest pursuits,
即追踪太阳系外的行星
the hunt for extra-solar planets.
就是现在  一种非常重要的蚀
a very important kind of eclipse right now
就是当一颗太阳系外  围绕另一颗恒星的行星
is the eclipse that occurs when an extra-solar planet,
格雷格·拉芙琳
加利福尼亚大学  圣克鲁兹
从恒星前面经过  这时候发生的蚀
a planet orbiting another star passes in front of the parent star.
这需要非常灵敏的望远镜才能探测到如此微小的亮度变化
It takes a very sensitive telescope to detect that slight dimming.
现在最著名的望远镜
The most famous telescope project right now
就是开普勒天文望远镜
is the Kepler space telescope
它正在太空中观察着超过十万颗像太阳一样的恒星
that is out there in space looking at over 100,000 sun-like stars
而且已经观察了好多年
and watching over a period of years
等待真正的像地球一样的
for the transits of actually Earth-like,
并且像地球一样大小的行星从那些恒星前面经过
Earth-sized planets going in front of those stars.
如果我们能够找到围绕其他恒星的行星就太好了
It'd be great if we could find planets orbiting other stars
只需要一架望远镜观测太空
by simply pointing a telescope up into the sky
然后拍张图片
and taking a picture of one.
但是真的很难
But that's really tough.
引起困难的原因之一
One of the reasons that that's really tough
娜塔莉·巴塔哈
圣何塞州立大学
因为这些恒星比绕着它转的行星
is because the stars are about 10 million
要亮一千万至一百亿倍
to 10 billion times brighter than the planets that orbit them.
我用这台探照灯就能简单地演示出来
I can demonstrate that really easily with this searchlight.
当我把灯打开
When I turn it on,
你会发现我完全消失在了耀眼的灯光中
you see that I become completely lost in the glare of this light,
就如同行星消失在它围绕的恒星所发出的光芒
just as a planet is lost in the glare of the star that it orbits.
开普勒的任务是测量恒星的亮度
Kepler's job is to measure the brightnesses of stars,
就像我们用测光表测量这台
just like we can do with this light meter and our simulated star,
模拟恒星的探照灯一样
the searchlight.
这便是蚀现象在任务中扮演的角色
This is how eclipses figure into the mission.
当物体从探照灯前经过  产生了蚀
The light meter's needle dips when something passes
测光表的指针便会偏转
in front of the searchlight, creating an eclipse.
这与开普勒的工作原理如出一辙
Kepler does the same thing,
但它要敏感得多
but is so sensitive
它能侦测到百万分之二十的亮度变化
it can detect a dip of 20 parts per million.
开普勒能够侦测到
Kepler is capable of detecting
适居带内围绕类日恒星运行的
an Earth-sized planet around a Sun-like star
与地球大小相近的行星
in the habitable zone.
也就是一个真正的类日地系统
So a real Earth-Sun analog,
这是开普勒能力所及的事
that's what Kepler is capable of doing.
这也是它能精确完成的第一个任务
And that's the first mission that's capable of doing exactly that.
开普勒瞄准了银河系中的一片区域
Kepler is trained on an area of the galaxy containing
那里大约有15万颗恒星
about 150,000 stars.
它不间断地监视着每颗恒星
And it monitors every one of them constantly,
每隔30分钟测量一次每颗恒星的亮度
measuring each star's brightness every 30 minutes,
希望能侦测到由围绕其中一些恒星运行的行星
hoping to detect those minute eclipses
引起的蚀现象
caused by planets around some of them.
只有一小部分的行星  能出现在适当的位置
Just a small fraction of them will be in the right position
使我们看见行星凌日现象
for us to see their planetary transits.
在天空中大部分恒星的行星系统中
Most of the stars in the sky that have planetary systems
都不会出现凌日现象
don't undergo transits.
只有当我们十分幸运地碰到这样一种情形
It's only if we have a lucky chance alignment
就是行星的轨道平面
where the orbital plane of the planet
与我们的视线平齐
is along our line of sight
或处在地球视线可见范围内
or contains our line of sight to the Earth
才能看到行星运行到恒星前时
that we can actually see when the planet goes in front of the star
遮蔽了恒星的部分光芒
and dims out some of the star's light.
这遥远的光影组合
The very distant combination of light and shadow
为每次凌日交织出一条的光变指示曲线
produces for each transit a telltale light curve
它显示了行星从恒星前穿过时
showing the dip in brightness
亮度的减弱
as the planet crosses in front of its sun.
仅仅工作了几个月后  开普勒就有了发现
Kepler produced results after only a few months on the job.
我们观察了第一批光变曲线
We looked at our very first light curves.
很快便发现了凌日现象
We could see transits immediately.
某些行星就这么突然从我们面前冒了出来
I mean, some of them just popped right out at us.
航天器的表现堪称完美
The spacecraft was performing flawlessly.
传回的数据相当惊艳
The data was beautiful.
我们一直想达到一个精准的层面
Right out of the gate,
以实现我们最初的期望
we were reaching the precision levels
现在我们离它只有一步之遥了
very close to what we expected at the beginning.
2010年1月
In January 2010,
开普勒团队宣布
The Kepler team announced
发现了5颗符合任务要求的行星
the discovery of the mission's first five planets.
四颗像木星一样巨大
four are gas giants like Jupiter,
第五颗  与海王星一般大
the fifth, the size of Neptune.
开普勒在第一周的搜寻中
Kepler saw their transits many times
就多次侦测到它们的凌日现象
in its first weeks of searching.
这意味着  它们的公转周期只有几天
It means they orbit their stars in a matter of days,
每次都会使它们的恒星形成蚀
eclipsing their stars each time.
这些行星很接近它们的恒星
These things are closer to their parent star,
大概比水星到太阳的距离
about 10 times closer to their parent star
还要近10倍
than Mercury is to our Sun.
而且水星是离太阳最近的行星
And Mercury is the closest planet to our Sun.
但开普勒最终的目标之一
But one of Kepler's ultimate goals
是寻找围绕类日恒星旋转的类地行星
is to find Earth-like planets around Sun-like stars,
这需要更长时间
and that takes longer,
因为它们的公转周期会与地球类似...即一年
since they will orbit on time scales like our own... once a year.
一颗围绕类日恒星旋转的类地行星
An Earth-like planet around a Sun-like star
将会减弱恒星亮度的万分之一
is going to produce a dimming of one part per 10,000.
这信号相当微弱
So it's a very tiny signal.
如果这发生在适居带
If it's in the habitable zone,
这种凌日信号将持续12小时
that signal, the transit is going to last 12 hours
一年出现一次
and would repeat once every year,
而不是三天一次
not once every three days.
因此你必须一直盯着
So you have to stare.
持之以恒
You have to have stability.
你要观测一整年才能等到一次
You stare for a whole year and you wait for an event that happens
它只持续12个小时  而且相当微小
and lasts 12 hours and is very, very tiny,
只有万分之一的变化
one part per 10,000.
当开普勒观测到合适的光变曲线时
When Kepler spots the right kind of light curve,
地面上的大型望远镜也不甘落后
large telescopes on the ground follow up.
它们进行其他测量
They take additional measurements
以确保这些蚀现象是由行星引起的
to be sure the eclipses are caused by planets.
这意味着要排查大量数据
It means weeding through a lot of data.
截至2010年6月  我们有将近700颗备选行星
As of June 2010, we had approximately 700 planet candidates.
地面望远镜进行的确认工作
The confirmation work now being done
痛苦而又漫长
by ground telescopes is painfully slow
而且还将持续几个月甚至几年的时间
and will continue for months and years to come.
随着侦测不断地进行
As the process continues,
开普勒发现的行星数目
Kepler's planet list is expected
将很快增长至数十上百个
to grow to dozens soon and later hundreds.
要验证开普勒的成功率多半靠猜测
Measuring Kepler's success rate is guesswork.
但可能有多达50%的备选星球
But as many as 50% or more of its candidates may turn out
都是真正的行星
to be actual planets.
在长达六年的时间里  开普勒将一直搜寻细微蚀现象
Kepler will search for tiny eclipses for as long as six years,
它积累的银河系中的行星资料
accumulating a census of planets in our galaxy more complete
比此前汇编的任何资料都完整
than any compiled so far.
开普勒会使我们明确
Kepler is going to determine
类地行星是普遍存在还是稀少罕见的
if Earth-like planets are common or rare,
不管答案如何  都会很有意思
and the answer either way is going to be very interesting.
如果它们十分罕见
If it turns out that they're rare,
那说明我们在银河系中是多么与众不同
that speaks to how special we are in the galaxy.
但是我们有理由相信
However, we have reason to believe
它们并不是银河系中的稀客
that they're going to be frequent.
我们都有点盲目乐观
I think we're all kind of closet optimists
认为它们将会十分普遍
that they're going to be very common.
不过我们不清楚
But we don't know.
我们还没有答案
We don't have the answer yet.
在探寻围绕其它恒星运行的类地行星的过程中
In this, the discovery of Earth-like planets around others stars,
蚀现象将成为实现这一切的关键工具
eclipses will be the tools making it possible,
这与那些见证日食的追寻者寻求的
far removed from the sensory thrill
感官刺激有天壤之别
that the chasers seek in witnessing the Moon block out our Sun.
外太空的蚀现象也许将指引我们
Eclipses in deep space may lead us
获取我们世界  乃至整个宇宙的终极知识
to the ultimate knowledge of our place in the cosmos.
用挡住宇宙中最耀眼天体的光芒的办法
By blocking out the light from some of the most luminous objects in creation,
就像是发出一声振聋发聩的呐喊
it is as if we are screaming out the deafening noise
现在  人们听到的
and are now hearing
只是宇宙那隐秘并充满揭示意义的窃窃私语
only the secret and revealing whispers of the universe.